Mio HC Mi Ultimate Health Care update
2025. Actually,
I discussed this MIUC product information 2 years ago,
but because there were changes, I
felt the need to repeat it again.
Please read the disclaimer
first.
Everyone may experience pain.
If you are sick, you want to get well.  To get better you
have to get treatment.
Medical treatment costs money.   The
hospital admin will ask, "Do you want to use your
own money or insurance?"  The
most appropriate answer is to use
Mio HC insurance from Manulif.
What is MIO HC?  Mi Ultimate Health Care?
Let's take a look at the product features.
MIUHC is a
traditional non-unitlink health insurance.   The
1 year coverage period can be
extended up to the age of 110 years.
Providing cashless facilities at
Manulai's selected hospitals in collaboration
with Halodc.
Pay claims according to the bill with a
limit of 4 to 30 billion per year
depending on the plan.  If that's not
enough, there's an additional booster limit
of 6 to 20 M for life.  The difference
between the two is that the annual limit is
used first and is
restored from the beginning every year.  Meanwhile,
if the booster limit has been used, the
following year the remainder will be used up.
But this limit booster can only be used
if the annual limit has been used up.  So you
can imagine that the disease must be
very serious if the booster limit is
used up because that means at least 4
M per year has been used up.
This product can be supplemented with outpatient benefits
, but it is only recommended for inpatients
.
Another feature is a
5% discount for family policies of at least 3
people.  For example, a husband and wife with one
child or a father with two children also
get a 5% discount.
There is a no claim discount in the form of a
10 to 15% reduction in the following year's premium.
10% discount if there are no claims in 1
year and 15% discount if there are no
claims in 2 consecutive years or
more.
There is also a no claim bonus in the form of an
additional annual limit of 10% to a maximum of
50%.  So, if there are no claims, the minimum annual limit of 4 M will
increase by 10%
to 4.4 M the following year.  The maximum increase is
50%.  So if the initial limit is 4, the
maximum is up to 6 M. That's the
lowest plan, right?
Then there is the option of a plan with a deductible
or own risk to save
up to 40% on premiums.
What is a deductible?  I'll explain later
when I discuss the plan.  Then there is another
MPMP Manulai Personal
Medical Partner service facility.  This is if the illness is serious.
So, this is an explanation of MPMP
Manulai Personal Medical Partner, which provides
comprehensive medical assistance for
customers suffering from serious illnesses.
Customers who participate in this service will
get access to world-renowned doctors
to get a second medical opinion
as well as professional medical advice
.   The
mentoring period is 3 months
and can be extended
and this is without additional costs, aka
free.
And this service is not only valid
for MIO HC but also for MIHC
Syariah, Miss HC riders, MCCP, and
Miss CCP riders.  The last two are
critical illness insurance.
Okay, next.  Well, here are the
Mio HC Mi Ultimate Health Care plan options, which were
updated in 2025. For plans, there are the
Z Indonesia and Z Indonesia Smart plans.
Then there are the Z and Z Smart.  There are Topas
Indonesia and Topas Indonesia Smart.
Topaz and Topaz Smart, Emerald and
Emerald Smart, Ruby and Ruby Smart, then
Diamond and Diamond Smart.  The
protected area starts from Indonesia alone,
then Asia except Singapore, Hong Kong,
Japan, and then the whole world except the
United States.  The room class of each line is
different.  There are two
beds, there are also one bed.
Even for one bed for the
top 3, the room price limits
vary.  What is seen is which one is
higher.  For example, plan J
Indonesia, here two beds or
rooms are Rp. 500,000 per day.  What if the
two-bedroom room costs
Rp. 800,000 per day?  yes, as long as
it is a two-bed room.  Or
if you take PL Topas which has a single
bed or room of R million per day,
what if the price of a single bed room
is R 2 million per day?
Can I come in?  Yes, you can, as long as it
is the lowest one-bed room
in the hospital.  The benefits
are generally according to the bill, whether it is the doctor,
medication, surgery, and so on.   The
annual limit plus booster starts
from 4 M to 6 M. And the
highest diamond plan is 30 m plus 20
m for the booster.  Then this deductible is
specifically for the smart Z Indonesia smart,
Zmart, Topas Indonesia smart plans and
so on.  Well, for the Z Indonesia
Smart and Z Smart plans, the deductible is
5 million per treatment.  Then for the
Topas Indonesia Smart and Topas Smart plans,
the deductible is 8 million per
treatment.  The Emerald Smart plan
is doubled to R10 million per treatment.
Ruby Smart is Rp. 15 million and Diamond Smart
is Rp. million per treatment.  Per
treatment means every time you are
hospitalized, not per year.  Well, the
smart plan with a deductible has a
premium that is 35 to 40% cheaper than the
standard plan.  The Jade
Indonesia Smart plan is 35% cheaper
than the J Indonesia plan.  And for J
Smart, it's 40% cheaper than plan
J. What's the example of this for Duaktibal?
For example, if someone takes the Jet Smart plan,
the deductible is IDR 5 million per
treatment.  Then he is treated and the
hospital costs are, for example, R30 million, then
Manulif will pay R25 million.
Meanwhile, the R million was paid by the
customer himself.  If you take the Emerald
Smart plan for example, the maintenance costs are R30
million, which means the R million is paid for
yourself.  Manual will pay R million.
This didactible is a definite number, a
fixed number.  So even if the
medical costs are Rp million or Rp billion, if the
ML Smart plan is duplicated, it will still be Rp 10
million each time you are treated.  So if
the medical costs are IDR billion, the customer only has to
pay IDR 10 million.  The R990 million
is covered by manual life.  I think
this smart plan is very interesting, very
smart, and I often recommend it to
customers because besides being up
to 40% cheaper, it also educates
customers to take better care of
their health.  So, if you get
sick, you'll immediately ask to be hospitalized because you'll have to
pay for it yourself
.  And if you manage to stay
healthy and there are no claims, then the
following year there will be a premium discount,
okay, this is the Mio HC Mi
Ultimate Health Care plan option.  Next, here is a
complete table of inpatient benefits
.  Here there are hospitalizations and
surgical procedures.  There is outpatient care associated
with inpatient care.  Included here is
outpatient care before and after
hospitalization.  Then there are cancer treatments, be it
chemotherapy, radiotherapy, targeted therapy,
immunotherapy, hormonal therapy, yes.  Then
cancer monitoring is also covered.
For example, if you have recovered from cancer, but
still need to have check-ups occasionally for
cancer, then that is also covered.
Dialysis is also covered.  Then there are
other benefits related to
hospitalization.  Here there is funeral
or death benefits related to
illness or accidents treated in
hospital.  The compensation is 30 million.
Applies the same to all plans.  This
figure may be a bit unclear.  You
can just read it on my blog.  There are
images that can be downloaded.
Okay, next is the outpatient benefits table
.  Although it is not recommended
.  For those of you who are asking whether there is
outpatient insurance?  Yes, there is an
answer.  But the limit is not large,
only IDR 10 million a year and the
other option is IDR million a year.  There is also a
copay or your own risk of 20%.  So,
if the outpatient costs, for example, IDR 1
million, then you have to pay IDR 200,000.   Rp.
800,000 is covered by Manu Life.
There is an additional premium outside the premium
for hospitalization.  So it is
optional or a choice.
Okay, next here I show
some examples of MIU HC premiums for
age representatives only.  0, 5, 10 and
so on.  This premium is per year
and can be monthly but higher.
If monthly it is higher 14%.
This premium is valid from September 20, 2025.
Here is the premium table for other plans.
Next, there are general provisions that you need to
know.  The entry age of participants is 30 days
to 70 years.  For child participants aged 30
days to 17 years.  Policy holder must be
at least 18 years old.  The coverage period is 1
year and can be extended up to the age of
110 years.  Family policies apply to
nuclear families.  Husband, wife and children aged
maximum 17 years, maximum 10 participants
.  5% discount for minimum 3 participants
.  And the plan taken must be the
same for all participants.
Then there is also a no claim discount in the form of a
10% premium discount if there are no claims
in 1 year and a 15% premium discount
if there are no claims in 2
consecutive years or more.  Then there is an
additional bonus limit of 10% of the
maximum annual limit of 50%.
If traveling abroad or
residing outside Indonesia for
a maximum of 6 consecutive months, except in
emergencies and except for
students aged 17 to 25 years.  So
for students it is permissible to stay abroad for more than 6
months.  Then, if there is
no room available according to the plan, you can
stay in a room above the plan for a maximum of 2 days
and will still be charged according to the bill.
After 2 days you have to go down to the room
where the plan has been completed.  If it doesn't go down
then proration applies.  So the claim is
not settled anymore.
Furthermore, the frequency of premium payments
can be annual, semi-annual, quarterly,
or monthly.  There is a multiplying factor, yes.
Premium payment methods can be via auto-
debit savings transfer or auto-debit
credit card.
Then there are things that need to be noted,
including that this product has no
cash value, meaning the premium is forfeited.  So
don't expect your premium to be returned, or even
partially returned, if you take
this product.  Then the premium increases every year
as age increases and
can experience repricing at any time, namely an
increase in premiums due to medical inflation factors
and claim ratios.  For example, the
last repricing was September 20,
2025. Well, for the following year, we
don't know whether there will be a repricing
or not, but it's possible.
So I said it at the beginning like this.
Then claims outside the Manulif
or Manulif Prevospital selected hospitals are subject to a copay
or self-risk of 20% with a
maximum of IDR million for the J Indonesia
to Topas plans including the smart plan and a
maximum of IDR 00 million for the Emerald
to Diamond plans including the smart plan.  So,
if you choose this product, make sure that
your area already has a Manif hospital of choice.
Next are the medical test requirements.  In
general, up to the age of 50, it is non-medical if you are
healthy.  If there is hospitalization,
there is still the possibility of being asked for a medical test.
Meanwhile, for those aged 51 and above, a
medical test will be required.  There are type E
and type F. Medical tests are carried out at
clinics or hospitals that collaborate
with Manulif and the costs are borne by
Manulif.
Then the waiting period.  Well, this also needs to
be considered for
accident treatment without a waiting period.  For
general illnesses it is 30 days.
For special diseases containing 18
diseases, the waiting period is 12 months or 1
year.  The waiting period for HIV and AIDS is
also 1 year.  Cataract
waiting period 2 years.
Pre-existing conditions are not covered
forever.  And this will be stated at the
beginning, when you apply if you
have had a previous illness and
if that illness cannot be covered
by Manulif, then Manul will
state it at the beginning whether you agree
or not.  Cancer.  Well, this is a
special disease.  However, if
it occurs within the first 90 days since the
policy became active or since the policy was reinstated, it
is considered pre-existing and will not be
covered forever.  Then the
cashless facility for special diseases has a
waiting period of 2 years.  So, this particular disease is
not covered in the first year
, in the second year it is covered but
the claim just leaks, and in the third year it
can be caseless for
this particular disease.  So I will convey the
limitations at the beginning for those of you
who want to take this product so that you
don't get disappointed later on.
Next, here are 18 specific diseases,
please just read them.  Here there are hernias,
tumors, lumps, cancer cysts, tuberculosis,
diabetes, hypertension, yes, and others.
Furthermore, the claim method can be cashless
or refund.  Rimbment pays
first and then submits a claim to Manulif.
Cashless facilities are available at
selected Manulif Hospitals in collaboration
with Halodc at home and abroad
according to the chosen plan.  Access claims
if any and your own risk will be
billed on the spot before leaving the
hospital.
Then how to register.  If you agree to
take this product, have received
an illustration and are satisfied with the premium
and benefits, the next step
is to meet with an agent to fill out the
SPAK, a health insurance application form
.  Just prepare the attachments,
photocopy or photo of your ID card.
Supporting documents, for example, credit cards or
savings books or medical documents, if
there are any, such as a child's birth certificate, family card.
Then pay the first premium.  So,
the premium is paid in advance and after that
wait for the underwriting process.  You will
be notified if the policy
is approved or if additional information is required
or if a medical test is requested.
OK, that's what I can
say.  Thank you for
your attention.  Sorry if there's anything
missing.  Please just ask
if you have any questions via the
comments column or contact me
directly at this contact.  Once again,
thank you.  See you in the
next video.  M.